appnext.com 2019-10-03

# Privacy Policy | Appnext

###### Last revised: 15 May, 2018.

Appnext is dedicated to providing internet users the highest level of transparency and control over the use of their data in online advertising. We adhere to the Self-Regulatory Principles set forth by the  **European Interactive Digital Advertising Alliance**  (EDAA). Appnext also adheres to the  **Interactive Advertising Bureau’s**  (IAB)  **Europe Self-Regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising.**

###### Introduction

This privacy policy (“ **Privacy Policy** “) explains how Appnext collects, use and share your information, in order to provide its advertising and mobile distribution and promotion services to its partners and clients (“ **Partners** “), including information that we collect when you visit our website, located at www.Appnext.com (“Website”).

Appnext collects your information through our software development kit (“ **SDK** “), APIs and similar technological solutions (together, the “ **SDK** “), which is integrated in third party mobile applications (“ **Publishers** “), in order to allow the tracking of mobile application use, installations and downloads, and to enable the serving of advertising and personalized content. In order to do this, our Publishers have to actively set parameters that allow for such integration and measurement. In such instances, information collected and processed may be provided to both the Publisher and other Partners.

We collect information under the direction of our Publishers, and have no direct relationship with the individuals (“ **End Users** “) whose information we process. We respect the right to privacy of Publishers and End Users. Your ability to make informed choices about the use of your information is important to us, so please read this Privacy Policy carefully to learn about your choices.

If not specifically defined herein, capitalized terms have the meaning given to them in our Terms and Conditions, which is available here.

###### What information we collect

We collect the following categories of information for the purposes listed below:

  * **When using our Website  **– our webserver will collect information like your IP-address, the website from which you were referred to our website, the webpages you are visiting on our Website, the browser you are using and its display settings, your operating system as well as date and duration of your visit. Further personal data will only be stored and processed if you voluntarily provide it to us, e.g. through a contact form.

  * **Device and app information**  – this category includes your device’s type and model, system language, the device’s operating system (such as Android or iOS), SDK version, mobile carrier name, mobile browsers installed on the device (such as Chrome or Safari), app history and usage information (such as information about running and installed apps on the device), information regarding downloads and installations of mobile applications and any information regarding in-app events (such as in-app purchases), your device’s IP address, and identifiers assigned to your device, such as its iOS Identifier for Advertising (IDFA), Android Advertising ID, or other types of unique device identifiers (a number uniquely allocated to your device by your device manufacturer).

  * **Ad information**  – this category includes information about the online ads and personalized content we have served (or attempted to serve) to you. It includes things like how many times an ad has been served to you, what page the ad appeared on, whether you viewed, clicked on or otherwise interacted with the ad, ad engagement history and whether you visited the Advertiser’s website, downloaded an app or purchased the product or service advertised.

  * **Location information**  – Appnext collects information about your general location (such as city and country). For example, we may use the IP address to identify your general location. This information does not tell us where your device is precisely located. This information is sent as a normal part of internet traffic. In addition, we also collect implicit location information, which allows us to infer that you are either interested in a place or that you might be at the place – this information does not actually tell us where your device is precisely located.

In addition, Appnext may collect the precise location of your device (using GPS signals, device sensors, Wi-Fi access points, Bluetooth signals, Beacons signals and cell tower ids that can be used to derive or estimate precise location, or other geo-location data), when location services have been enabled by the end user for the mobile app or website that uses our SDK (you typically have to choose to turn on device-based location services).

  * **Log information**  – this category includes the app or website visited, session start/stop time, time zone, and network connection type (e.g., WiFi, cellular), and cookie information.

  * **Information from advertising partners (“Advertisers”) and other third parties**  – this category includes information we receive from our Publishers, Advertisers and other Partners that we work with to help us deliver ads and personalized content to you and recognize you across browsers and devices. This may include pseudonymous advertiser identifiers that some Advertisers or other third party ad platforms choose to share with us. This information is also used to enhance data points about a particular unique browser or device.

###### How We Use the Information We Collect

We use the information we collect for the following purposes:

  * **Serving ads and promoting apps**  – allow our Publishers to promote advertising, apps and content in their mobile apps, and to allow Advertisers to bid on Publishers’ inventory.

  * **Serve interest-based advertising and personalized content**  – enable our partners to infer interests and serve ads and personalized content to users based on their behavior, app activity and inferred interests. We will not serve interest-based ads or personalized content based on information that we consider sensitive, such as race, religion or health.

  * **Ad reporting and conversions**  – measure ad performance, report to Advertisers when and how users have viewed or clicked on their ads, or visited their website, and to report to Publishers when and how ads were shown on their properties and were clicked on.

  * **Analytics and frequency capping**  – allow our Publishers to analyze their applications (for this purpose, we use aggregated and anonymous benchmark data) and prevent users from seeing the same ad too many times.

  * **Fraud detection and prevention**  – identify invalid or incentivized clicks (or ad queries) and protect Appnext and our partners from fraudulent behavior.

  * Enforce our policies, resolve disputes and communicate with you.

  * **Providing and improving our services**  – audit, research and analyze information in order to maintain, protect, and improve our services and develop new services, and to ensure that our technologies function properly.

###### Information Sharing

We share information about you with:

  * **A Publisher whose app you have accessed to**  – we share information about how you have interacted with that Publisher’s app and its ads and personalized content.

  * **An Advertiser whose site or app you have visited**  – we share information about how you have interacted with that Advertiser’s site, app or its ads.

  * **With our service providers**  – we contract with companies who help with parts of our business operations (for example, storage of information). We require that our service providers only use your information in connection with the services they perform for us.

  * With our subsidiaries and related companies.

  * **In connection with legal proceedings**  – when we are under a legal obligation to do so, for example to comply with a binding order of a court, or where disclosure is necessary to exercise, establish or defend the legal rights of Appnext, our Partners or any other third party.

  * **In connection with a sale of our business**  – if a third party acquires some or all of our business or assets, we may disclose your information in connection with the sale.

  * In addition, we may disclose aggregated, anonymized information with other third parties. This information cannot be used to identify you.

###### How We Collect Information

When operating our services, we use various technological tracking tools to collect information from your device, such as:

  * Our SDK – the SDK is a bit of computer code that app developers (such as our Publishers) can include in their apps to enable ads and personalized content to be shown, data to be collected, and related services to be implemented.

  * Along with our Partners, we may use tracking technologies such as cookies, JavaScript, beacons and Local Storage such as HTML5. Our Partners may also use Local Storage Objects (LSOs) such as Flash. Local Storage (LS) such as HTML5 and Local Storage Objects (LSOs) such as Flash are used to store content information and preferences. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5 LS’s. Beacons are clear graphic image(s) of 1×1 pixel that is delivered through a web browser usually as part of a webpage request. Web beacons operate as a tag that records an end users visit to a particular webpage.

  * Our Publisher may use cookies to track your behavior on their apps or websites. A cookie is a small piece of text that is sent to a browser. The browser provides this piece of text to the originating server when the visitor returns. Most web browsers are initially configured to accept cookies, but you can change this setting so your browser either refuses all cookies or informs you when a cookie is being sent. Also, you are free to delete any existing cookies at any time. Please note that some features of Appnext may not function properly when cookies are disabled or removed.

  * JavaScript is a dynamic object oriented computer programming language. JavaScript is used to understand the End User’s behavior on an app or website.

You can learn more about the tracking tools we use by visit here.

###### Online Behavioral Advertising

Appnext complies with Self-Regulatory Principles set forth by the  **European Interactive Digital Advertising Alliance**  (EDAA). Appnext also adheres to the  **Interactive Advertising Bureau’s**  (IAB)  **Europe**  Self-Regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising

We use third parties who collect data about their apps’ and sites’ visitors through their own cookies, web beacons, and other technologies regarding your online activities, in an effort to understand your interests and deliver you advertisements that are tailored to your interests.

These third parties include Publishers, Advertisers and ad networks that may collect information about when you view or interact with one of their advertisements and may collect information regarding your online activities over time and across different apps and websites.

Like most Advertisers, we place advertisements where we think they will be most relevant to the recipient. When an End User visits a third-party website or app on which that network advertising company has purchased ad space, the advertising company can then recognize the individual’s interest and deliver one of our advertisements.

###### End User choice and Opt Out

Appnext supports initiatives of greater transparency and control for users, and offers the following options for controlling the interest-based content and ads you receive.

To serve personalized content and ads we may use technologies that perform similar functions to cookies. Sometimes we link the identifier used for advertising on mobile applications to an advertising cookie on the same device in order to coordinate ads across your mobile apps and mobile browser. This also helps us improve the reports we give to our advertisers on the effectiveness of their campaigns.

To opt out of personalized ads in apps on your mobile device, follow the instructions below.

**If you have an Android device –**

  1. Find Google Settings – depending on your device, it could be located here: 
    1. A separate app called  **Google Settings**
    2. In your main  **Settings**  app, scroll down and tap  **Google**
  2. Tap  **Ads**
  3. Switch on  **Opt out of interest-based ads**

**If you have an iOS device –**

If you have an iOS device, you can opt out of interest-based or “cross-app” advertising by updating to iOS 6.0 or higher, and setting  **Limit Ad Tracking**  to  **‘ON’**. You can do this by clicking on  **Settings**  ->  **General**  ->  **About**  ->  **Advertising**  and toggling  **Limit Ad Tracking**  to  **‘ON’**.

When you have opted out using these settings on a device, Appnext will not use in-app information collected from that device to infer your interests or serve ads to that device that are targeted based on your inferred interests. Appnext requires its Partners to honor opt-out preferences expressed using these controls. However, please note that opting-out using these settings would only prevents serving tailored ads to you;  **this would not affect other activities** , such as serving contextual advertising, ad frequency capping and analytics.

You can turn off certain third party cookies for advertising purposes by visiting the Network Advertising Initiative, located here: <http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/> or the DAA opt-out program, which are located here:<http://www.aboutads.info/choices/>, here (for EU/EEA citizens): <http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/> and here (for mobile devices): <http://www.aboutads.info/appchoices>

**Do Not Track Disclosure**

Do Not Track (“DNT”) is a privacy preference that users may set in certain web browsers. DNT is intended to allow users another method of informing websites and services that they do not want certain information about their website visits collected over time and across websites. Because the effect of DNT signals remains unclear, and there continues to be no consistent industry understanding of how to respond to such a signal, we do not alter our privacy practices when we detect a DNT signal from your browser. Rather, we provide or respect the consumer choice options set forth in this privacy policy.

###### Information Retention

We retain personally identifiable information we process on behalf of our Partners for as long as needed to provide services to them. We retain and use this information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

###### End User Rights

If you reside in the EU or in a different jurisdiction that affords you with the below rights, you may contact us at any time by [data-privacy@Appnext.com](mailto:data-privacy@appnext.com) and request to:

  * Receive confirmation as to whether or not personal information concerning you is being processed, and access your stored personal information, together with certain supplementary information.

  * Receive personal information you directly volunteer to us in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format.

  * Request rectification of your personal information.

  * Request erasure of your personal information.

  * Object to the processing of personal information by us.

  * Request to restrict processing of your personal information by us.

  * Lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority.

Please note that these rights are not absolute and requests are subject to any applicable legal requirements. In addition, we may not be able to exercise your request in the event we cannot identify you

In addition, we may rectify, replenish or remove incomplete or inaccurate information, at any time and at our own discretion, in accordance with our internal policies.

###### Security

Appnext has implemented reasonable security measures in order to protect your information from loss, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration or destruction. While we cannot guarantee that loss, misuse or alteration to information will not occur; we make good faith efforts to prevent such occurrences. We do not warrant or represent that your account or any of your information will be protected against, loss, misuse, or alteration by third parties.

## International transfers

Appnext may transfer the information we collect about you to countries other than the country where we originally collected it for the purposes of storage and processing of information and operating our services. Those countries may not have the same information protection laws as your country. However, when we transfer your information to other countries, we will protect that information as described in this Privacy Policy and take steps, where necessary, to ensure that international transfers comply with applicable laws. For example, if we transfer your information from the European Economic Area to a country outside it, such as the United States, we will seek to take additional steps such as entering into EU compliant data transfer agreements(model clauses) with the data importer where necessary.

###### Children Information

Appnext does not knowingly collect any personally identifiable information (including persistent device identifiers) relating to children under the age of consent (namely, below the age where consent must by given or authorized by the holder of parental responsibility over the child, as required the applicable law in the jurisdiction you reside in (“Age of Consent”). In addition, we require our Publishers to certify to us that their services (such as their mobile apps) are not primarily directed to appeal to children under the age of Age of Consent, and to avoid sharing with us any personally identifiable information relating to children under the age of Age of Consent.

Please note that while we strive hard to ensure that our policies are respected, we cannot be held responsible for the practices of our Publishers. Our publishers are responsible to ensure that their privacy practices comply with applicable privacy laws and requirements, including with respect to safeguarding children’s privacy (such as by complying with the U.S. Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998).

If you have knowledge of any incident in which we may be collecting personal data relating to children under the Age of Consent, or that our SDK is included in any service (such as a mobile app) that is directed to or aimed to appeal to audience under the Age of Consent, please let us know immediately by contacting us at: [data-privacy@Appnext.com](mailto:data-privacy@appnext.com), and we will remove their personally identifiable information from our servers without delay.

###### Changes to Our Privacy Practices

We may update this privacy policy to reflect changes to our privacy practices, from time to time. If we make any material changes we will post such amendment on our website, prior to the change becoming effective; material changes will become effective seven (7) days as of the date we posted the notice on our website. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices (the last change will be reflected in the “last updated” date above).

###### Have Any Questions or Comments?

If you have any questions, concerns or feedback about our privacy policy, please don’t hesitate to contact us our Data Protection Officer at [data-privacy@Appnext.com](mailto:data-privacy@appnext.com). We will make our best efforts to respond to you in a timely manner.

You can also mail us your inquiries through our EU representative:

  * Appnext Ltd.

  * Attn: Data Protection Officer

  * 1 Anpauseos street, 2nd Floor,

  * Limassol, 3096,

  * Cyprus.

Our contact details:  
Appnext Ltd., a BVI corporation, Intershore Chambers, Road Town, Tortola, British Virgin Islands, 4342.
